Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Look.
This is a tentative list of Yun-e’s
crimes that the officials have put together.
There are eight crimes in total.
Disrespecting the emperor;
Betraying the prior emperor;
Forming a faction for personal interests;
Undermining the authority of the court;
Repressing channels of reports;
Assaulting officials;
Subverting the emperor;
And abusing military influence.
Any one of these is a capital offense and unpardonable.
These are all facts.
He's not being treated unjustly.
Is Your Majesty really going to sentence him to death?
I have to forgive even the unforgivable.
I cannot be seen as an emperor who executes
his own brothers because of this.
It’s not worth it over someone like him.
Given State Prince Dun’s military achievement
and extended service,
and the fact that he is my brother,
I don’t have the heart to kill him
and foil the expectations of our late father.
Thus, I am going to spare him from death.
He is to be deprived of his noble status
and demoted to commoner.
He will be imprisoned in the Imperial Clan Court
for the rest of his life.
No one will visit him without my permission.
And what about his wife, Princess Gonding,
and the banner prince?
They will be reduced to commoners as well.
However, I have allowed them to stay in their residence.
This is also the Empress Dowager’s wish.
Now that Yun-e has been convicted,
the next step is to eliminate his supporters.
This is the most critical.
An official suggested that I rule
with strict laws and harsh punishments.
That I should execute his entire clan, to set
an example and prevent further turmoil.
And what does Your Majesty think?
There is some sense to it.
Your Majesty, memorandums from the
Northwest have arrived for your review.
Nian Gengyao is quick on his feet.
Nian Gengyao's memorandums arrived
right after State Prince Dun's incident.
I believe he is trying to discover Your Majesty's position.
These are congratulatory messages on
the auspicious signs in Heaven.
Just more of the same. I don’t feel like reading it.
You read it to me.
Your Majesty, I dare not read it.
What’s the matter?
Let me take a look.
Your Majesty, these are audacious words of rebellion.
Inappropriate for Your Majesty's viewing.
Hand it over.
The four characters 朝乾夕惕
[work tirelessly from morning to sunset]
are re-ordered and written sloppily.
It reads 夕陽朝乾
[A waning sun worked hard]
General Nian might have just been careless in his writing.
Nian Gengyao is never a careless person.
He doesn't think that I deserve this praise.
Given this,
I might not acknowledge his merits in Qinghai.
I’ve already warned him time and again
due to previous disturbances.
I said that an official who devotes himself to the country
must speak with integrity and be clear as daylight.
However, he has become conceited over his merits
and has been disrespectful to me.
This mistake is not unintended.
May peace be restored in Your Majesty.
How about marking this disrespectful phrase and
sending it back to allow him a chance to explain?
So he can account for himself to Your Majesty.
What’s left to explain? It’s written in black and white.
Your Majesty, allow him a chance to respond.
If this becomes more serious, at least
he had an opportunity to defend himself.
Su Peisheng!
Your Majesty.
Send this back
to the Northwest as it is.
It must be delivered to Nian Gengyao directly.
Yes.
Announce this decree: Nian Gengyao’s close ally, the
Governor of Gansu Province, Hu Qiheng, is dismissed.
The Acting Commander of Sichuan Province, Na Tai,
will be relocated to the capital.
I will do this immediately.
Zhou Ninghai, say it clearly.
Your Highness,
The Great General was extending
congratulations for the auspicious signs in Heaven.
But he may have made a mistake writing a phrase.
What phrase?
The Great General wrote 朝乾夕惕 as 夕陽朝乾.
That’s all fine.
It’s just careless writing.
But His Majesty was infuriated!
What about the memorandum?
His Majesty sent it back ...
without commenting.
Your Highness …
"Today is different from the past."
Last time His Majesty investigated my brother’s servants.
This time, even though State Prince Dun’s
incident is not directly related to my brother ...
But whether His Majesty tolerates this mistake ...
Now His Majesty didn't even comment on the letter ...
I am afraid this is not good.
Your Highness, you need to help the Great General.
What can I do?
I can only tell my brother to demonstrate his loyalty,
and plead for His Majesty’s forgiveness.
Go check if His Majesty is available to meet me.
Yes,
right away!
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao abuses his power and indulges his arrogance;
accumulates power and receives bribes；
purges dissidents and gathers supporters;
claims false military contributions
and embezzles the country’s wealth,
murders innocent people
and persecutes good citizens.
His crimes are uncountable.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao has been severely deceiving you.
He is neither loyal nor law-abiding.
Anyone can execute him and it would be just.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao betrays Your Majesty's favor and the nation.
His crimes deserve capital punishment.
However, he holds high rank and great military power.
He is far away in the Northwest
and has numerous supporters.
We must not rush this.
Otherwise, he might attempt a military coup.
I suggest Your Majesty consider
immediate condemnation and delayed punishment.
Nian Gengyao does not observe the obligations of an official.
His acts are unlawful and blatant, without any fear.
If I do not punish him,
how can I calm the anger of the people
and restore order in the government?
If any of Nian Gengyao's supporters
remain
faithful to him,
if they betray the country for self-interests,
outwardly condemn and secretly abet,
once discovered,
they will be convicted of treason and punished severely.
We obey Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
This is Nian Gengyao's explanatory memorandum.
Take a look.
Nian Gengyao recites his loyalty
to Your Majesty over all these years.
His words are reasoned.
But my concern is this:
Nian Gengyao has made such a detailed list
that he seems to be boasting of his achievements
to intimidate Your Majesty.
Nian Gengyao dares to overstate his merits
even at this time.
It's apparent
that he wants to clear his name and avoid punishment,
so he ventures to pose his power as a menace to his master.
I believe the same.
His thoughts are, I'm afraid,
that without him, I cannot
bring peace and stability to the country.
Nian Gengyao has always flaunted his achievements,
and Your Majesty has repeatedly
tolerated him, increasing his arrogance.
The guilty official Yun-e sent Nian Gengyao
messages before attempting the rebellion.
Your Majesty only intercepted one of them.
There must have been more prior to this one.
Nian Gengyao did not report this rebellious scheme.
Instead, he earned Yun-e's trust
to join forces with him.
If anyone would claim that Nian Gengyao
was completely innocent,
I would not believe it.
Nian Gengyao has sorely disappointed me.
I have endured him long enough.
I don't need to anymore.
Nian Gengyao is to be deprived of his role as
the Governor of Sichuan and Shaanxi
[militarily critical region]
and demoted to the General of Hangzhou.
His previous post will be filled by Yue Zhongqi.
Zhang Tingyu,
draft an imperial decree accordingly.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I heard my brother's explanatory memorandum
has been presented to His Majesty.
I wonder how it's been received.
His Majesty has always treated
Your Highness's family generously.
No matter how angry His Majesty is,
a few reprimanding words or a cut in stipends will do it.
Don't be too worried, Your Highness.
Recent troubles never seem to end,
Although His Majesty favors you,
and treats me as usual,
my heart is never at peace.
Your Highness hasn't been able to rest well
since the restoration of your status.
If this continues,
it may harm Your Highness's health.
Your Highness, Your Highness, terrible news!
The Great General has been stripped of his position
as the Governor of Sichuan and Shaanxi.
Your Highness.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty,
Your Majesty seems to be in good spirits today.
Indeed.
Lately, I have been busy with state affairs
and was not in the mood to hear you sing.
Yes, I have not seen Your Majesty for quite some time.
You haven't.
Do you still have the energy to play the moon lute?
I have not seen Your Majesty lately,
so my fingers have become rusty.
What happened to your wrist?
It's nothing. It's almost healed.
Don't hide anything from me.
I see Sourire as my sister.
After Sourire's miscarriage,
although she recovered,
her body was still weak.
I heard that using human blood as a catalyst
can boost one's health most effectively.
So I cut my wrist to provide my blood for Sourire.
A superstitious belief. You acted foolishly.
But Souririe's health has improved significantly,
hasn't it?
That day, when I exiled Concubine Sourire to Penglai Island,
you came to see me, insisting on going with her.
From that moment, I knew you had forged a
sisterly bond with Concubine Sourire.
If you had not followed her,
her days would have been more difficult.
I share all weals and woes with Sourire.
That was what I had to do.
From now on,
I wish to accompany Your Majesty more often, together with Sourire.
Stop the sedan, stop the sedan.
Stop immediately.
Your Highness.
Peace to Consort Fleur.
Peace to Companion Zhi.
Is His Majesty inside?
Lady An is with His Majesty.
- Get out of my way!
- By His Majesty's decree,
Your Highness need not pay respects to
His Majesty these days.
Why does His Majesty refuse to see me?
I don't dare to speculate on His Majesty's decree.
Your Highness, I hope Your Highness will reconsider.
Your Highness, Your Highness!
Your Majesty,
my brother did not intend to challenge your authority,
Writing 夕陽朝乾 was an unintended mistake.
I beg Your Majesty to forgive my brother
on account of his past merits. Your Majesty!
Your Highness,
this will only make your own situation worse.
It's not worth it.
I must kneel here
until His Majesty is willing to see me.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, Her Highness Consort Fleur
is begging so fervently outside,
do you wish to see her?
I knew she would come;
I summoned you in order to avoid her.
But, Consort Fleur is pleading so pitifully outside.
She has disturbed Your Majesty's peace.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Go tell Consort Fleur that
if she wants to make me angry, she can cry harder.
Yes.
Your Majesty!
Meizhuang, you are quite leisurely and care-free.
You are here.
Do you still blame me?
If I were, I would have let you freeze on Penglai Island,
instead of sending you winter clothing.
I am totally regretting that.
Your regret is too late.
I'm wearing them now.
It was all my fault that day.
I should not have doubted you.
On that day, I could not tell you,
since it was related to state affairs,
which led you to misunderstand me.
I was not in my right mind that day.
How could I say those words to you?
Meizhuang, your words may be harsh but your heart is tender.
I know you well.
I heard Nian Gengyao has lost his power,
and Consort Fleur's position is precarious.
Companion Zhi also moved out.
A precarious position is insufficient.
In the same way as you,
I am also waiting to see the great tower tumble.
However, we are not her close associates.
Our knowledge of her is limited.
It's time to make use of someone.
Consort Fleur's brother was demoted because
he was disrespectful to His Majesty.
I know that
none of you are fond of Consort Fleur.
However, we are living in the palace together.
We should console her during this time.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Although we feel sorry for Consort Fleur,
her brother Nian Gengyao has only himself to blame.
He is always arrogant and domineering,
and displays no restraint even in front of His Majesty.
Had he recognized his fault early,
he wouldn't have been reprimanded by all the officials now.
Your Highness, I beg your forgiveness.
What's going on?
I have concealed something from Your Majesty
But now I dare not continue.
Go ahead and tell me.
In the Summer Palace a few years ago,
Consort Fleur had someone put cassava starch
into Princess Wenyi's water chestnut porridge.
And they attempted to frame Concubine Sourire.
When her attempt failed,
she turned Xiao Tang from the
Imperial Kitchen into a scapegoat.
Since you know the truth,
why didn't you reveal it until today?
I didn't know, Your Majesty!
I was deceived by Consort Fleur,
trusting that it was Concubine Sourire's doing.
Until one day I saw
Consort Fleur ordering Xiao Tang to take the blame.
But Consort Fleur accidentally noticed my presence.
So she threatened that
if I dared to tell others,
she would take custody of Princess Wenyi!
Poor little Wenyi.
She suffered so much at such a young age.
I understand deeply how Lady Cao feels.
As a mother, how can you not be
scared over losing your child?
Everyone has doubts about Wenyi's poisoning incident.
However, His Majesty didn't investigate thoroughly
for the good name of the imperial family.
If what you say is true, Consort Fleur is vicious indeed.
Although she is not the birth mother of Wenyi,
how could she lay murderous hands on a baby?
But Your Highness, Xiao Tang was flogged to death.
The dead tell no tales.
Consort Fleur instructed two maids
to say that they witnessed Concubine Sourire
passing by my residence.
Later, Consort Honnête pointed out that
this accusation was false.
Consort Fleur‘s intentions are obvious.
My poor Wenyi
was used as a pawn while still in swaddling clothes!
Concubine Sourire,
you were involved in this.
Do you have anything to say?
I was indeed wronged that day.
I am aware. Have a seat.
I thank Your Majesty.
Jiang Fuhai.
Your Majesty.
Bring Consort Fleur here.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Highness ...
About the Great General,
there is now another decree.
What did His Majesty say?
His Majesty...
Just say it.
I can bear any news.
General Nian is deprived of the position of prince mentor
and the first-order hereditary chieftaincy.
The posts held by his sons
Nian Fu and Nian Xing are also removed.
My brother is punished for his mistakes.
But why should Nian Fu and Nian Xing be implicated?
His Majesty is still enraged,
which is why he refuses to see Your Highness.
Peace to Your Highness.
What is it?
Your Highness, Her Majesty requests to see you immediately.
All right,
I also want to see the Empress.
Go.
I beg Your Majesty's pardon.
There's one more thing I've been afraid to say.
Don't be afraid to speak out.
Noble Lady Chun's death wasn't an accident.
Didn't Lady Chun drown?
As far as I know,
Lady Chun was a skilled swimmer.
You, go on.
Lady Chun went to the lakeside for her kite
and I was also playing with the princess
behind a rock mountain.
I didn’t expect to see ...
Consort Fleur’s servant Zhou Ninghai
cruelly pressing Lady Chun into the water.
She died after moments of struggling.
Zhou Ninghai then pushed Lady Chun into the water
and staged the scene as if she drowned.
And then?
I ...
I was so frightened ...
My only thought was to leave as fast as I could.
However, the princess cried out at that moment
and Consort Fleur heard.
My arms and legs were failing me in fright.
Consort Fleur threatened me that
if I dared to tell anyone,
she would kill me and the princess.
I was so scared.
Consort Fleur ...
She dared to kill Lady Chun in the palace ...
She would also dare to kill me and the princess.
Every night I dreamed of that
tortured scene of Lady Chun’s death.
I can't stand it anymore.
But why did she kill Lady Chun?
Later I tried to uncover the truth
and found that
Lady Chun overhead Consort Fleur
taking bribes from officials.
She introduced them to General Nian
who aided in their promotions.
That was why she was killed.
Your Majesty, how can Consort Fleur be so audacious?
No wonder she loves extravagance
and her palace spends money like running water.
I thought her money came from Nian Gengyao.
Who would think that she dared accept bribes?
How much did she receive?
I can't be sure.
At least hundreds of thousands of taels.
His Majesty resents corrupt officials the most.
I never thought they had found their way to the harem!
Bitch!
Consort Fleur, this is my palace!
How dare you be so brazen!
You say you don't allow it,
but I've acted this way many times.
You won't mind one more time.
Bitch, bitch!
How dare you betray me?
Have you forgotten how you gained your status?
And how you were ready to do anything
to curry favor with me?
You betrayed my trust!
You all heard!
The words came out of her own mouth.
She has close ties to Lady Cao.
Therefore, what Lady Cao said is credible.
Autumn, report to His Majesty.
Order the Department of Penalty to harshly interrogate her servants.
Yes.
Is it you?
Or the Empress?
Or one of you
who instructed this bitch to vilify me?
No one is going to defame Your Highness.
"The crime no one knows about
is the crime you've never committed."
You all are throwing stones at me now that
I've fallen into a well.
"All hands push when the wall is collapsing!"
You don't seem capable of
answering any questions today.
Leave.
And stop acting like a shrew in the market.
You are still His Majesty’s consort.
Whatever you want to know,
you may come ask me in my palace.
I’ll await Your Majesty.
After enduring her for so many years,
I finally get to have this day.
What satisfaction!
Everyone in her palace must be interrogated
with no exception!
Especially Zhou Ninghai!
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Lingzhi ...
Did you hear that?
Is Zhou Ninghai being tortured?
Your Highness, don't give yourself a fright.
It's been two days and two nights.
A confession has been extorted from
anyone ever sent to the Department of Penalty.
They can even dig words out of the dead.
Your Highness, what if he ...
I don't regret a single thing I did.
If he makes confessions to save himself,
I won't blame him.
I will take the punishment.
I only hope that His Majesty will not impose
any more punishment on my brother
on account of his past service.
Is there no more Pleasancy in the censer?
Go, refill it.
Yes.
Peace to Your Highness.
What is it this time?
Her Majesty is aware that Your Highness
is concerned about your brother,
so I'm here to inform Your Highness.
My brother received successive demotions,
but His Majesty still hasn't shown any mercy?
When General Nian had just arrived
in the Jiangsu-Zhejiang region,
rumor flared up that
General Nian accused His Majesty of
"trusting libellers instead of a loyal officer".
He even audaciously stated that
"A new emperor will rise from Sanjiangkou in Zhejiang
with Jiahu Lake being his battlefield."
How can anyone trust this rumor?
My brother would never make
such a rebellious remark.
"If you want to incriminate someone,
you can always find a pretext."
Your Highness,
words are spread by others
but deeds are done by oneself.
You have no one else but him to blame.
General Nian refused to continue his travel
when he arrived in Yizheng City of Jiangsu.
He ordered other officials to preserve his position
as the Governor of Sichuan-Shaanxi.
His Majesty furiously reproached him for intentionally delaying.
So His Majesty just granted a decree
that General Nian will be demoted to
a city wall guard of Hangzhou.
Your Highness,
what an announcement "freshly off the stove"!
Is his Majesty is really so merciless?
Your Highness, please wake up!
Your Highness.
Your Majesty, here's the record of
Zhou Ninghai's confession.
It mentions
the cassava starch incident Lady Cao referred to,
the death of Lady Chun,
receiving bribes to vouch for court officials,
and also instructing Yu to poison Concubine Sourire,
pushing Lady Vertu into the pond and
defaming her with a feigned pregnancy,
and sending her utensils from
a servant who contracted the plague
which caused Lady Vertu's infection.
And other deliberate attempts to harm the concubines.
It's presented for Your Majesty's review.
Did Zhou Ninghai spit out everything he should?
Your Majesty,
Zhou Ninghai fell unconscious
twice during interrogation.
He admitted that this was all he knew
and he wasn't aware of anything else.
Is there anything else?
Hasn't Consort Fleur afflicted enough ills?
Take this away.
Consort Fleur's crimes are too numerous to be counted.
What will Your Majesty do about Consort Fleur?
Go and investigate
all in the palace who have been in
contact with Consort Fleur.
Flog to death those found to be suspicious.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Consort Fleur of the Nian family
lacks virtue and morality.
She is to be deprived of her honorary name
and demoted to the rank of Companion.
Your Majesty has a benevolent heart and
treats the harem with leniency.
I'm sure Companion Nian will
correct her mistakes and start anew.
I thank Your Majesty on behalf of Companion Nian.
However, Companion Nian insists on seeing Your Majesty.
Presumably to appeal to Your Majesty
and plead for mercy on her family.
I no longer have anything to say to her.
I still remember when she first married into the family.
How bright and vivacious she was.
Why has she become like this today?
Companion Nian has no one but
herself to blame.
Who has been selected from the
meritorious families to enter the palace?
I need to show acknowledgment of these families.
As per Your Majesty's bidding,
I have selected Censor Gūwalgiya Emin’s
daughter Gūwalgiya Wenyuan
and Li Ying, the sister of General Li Bin
from the Valiant Calvary Brigade.
I await Your Majesty's decision.
- The Li family is of the Han banners?
- Yes.
The Gūwalgiya family is of the
Manchu Bordered Yellow Banner [the highest banner].
There aren't many concubines from the Manchu banners.
- We can add another one.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Which rank would Your Majesty like to grant her?
I've selected two names
Délice [delight] and Bonté [goodness],
either of which can be used as an honorary name.
She will be ... Noble Lady Délice.
- And enter the palace on the first of November.
- Yes.
And what will Your Majesty do about Companion Zhi?
Let her be.
She can still serve as a maid to Companion Nian.
Your Majesty,
Lady Cao was also quite intimate with Companion Nian.
Lady Cao.
If you were well aware of
Companion Nian's ill doings,
why didn't you speak up until today?
I do beg Your Majesty's pardon.
I really didn't dare to before.
Companion Nian was imperious and had harmed many concubines.
While under her power,
to protect myself and Princess Wenyi,
I was compelled to keep quiet.
But now that Wenyi is growing older,
I don't want her to be coerced like I have been.
My own life is undeserving of pity,
but Wenyi is Your Majesty's child after all.
It's only after Your Majesty has pacified the court
that I have found the courage to report to Her Majesty.
I shouldn't have felt compelled by Nian.
I'm willing to take any punishments.
But I hope Your Majesty will not put any
blame on the princess.
Your Majesty, Lady Cao was forced
to do so against her will.
And the princess is still young ...
Lady Cao has suffered so much for Princess Wenyi.
Your Majesty should appease Lady Cao instead.
Noble Lady Cao Qinmo, exposing Nian's offenses
is a merit!
She is promoted to the rank of Concubine
and granted the honorary name Aide.
The promotion ceremony will be
held on the first of November.
I am grateful to Your Majesty's heavenly grace.
What was the outcome?
She was not granted suicide.
Then was she banished to the Cold Palace?
She was only demoted to Companion,
and stripped of her honorary name.
She's even permitted to stay
in the Palace of Earthly Honor.
What?
That is it?
His Majesty knows of all her offenses.
It's clear His Majesty still has affections for her,
and is conscience-stricken.
Then what about Cao Qinmo?
Only half of what she said was the truth.
She absolved herself from all liability.
At most, she's seen as a helpless mother
coerced by a favored consort.
Deserving of sympathy and forgiveness.
Cao Qinmo is much cleverer than Consort Fleur.
Without Cao Qinmo,
Consort Fleur is a hawk ...
but with a broken wing:
impetuous and going in circles.
She is incapable of doing anything when
she is bitten back at.
Your Majesty is still concerned about
what Nian Gengyao did?
I've already dismissed Nian Gengyao of all his duties.
And ordered him to be a guard at the local city gate.
If he had acted within the bounds of propriety,
I wouldn't have wanted to be ruthless.
But while guarding the city gate
how dare he wear the imperial yellow gown I granted!
His ostentatious acts churned up rumor and commotion.
Causing everyone to think I'm a
cruel and unjust emperor!
Nian Gengyao probably intended
to use the imperial yellow gown
to remind Your Majesty of his good deeds in the past.
However, he is only thinking of himself,
and has no consideration for Your Majesty's reputation.
What is good about him that I should be reminded of?
The court officials have already convicted
Nian Gengyao of five offenses of rebellion,
nine offenses of deception,
and sixteen offenses of usurpation
and thirteen offenses of insolence.
In total, he committed ninety-two offenses.
Any one of them is worthy of execution by law.
Your Majesty.
Companion Nian is outside requesting an audience.
Your Majesty!
Rejected.
But Your Majesty,
Companion Nian has come here three times.
She has even wounded her forehead
from bowing to the ground.
Go tell her
it is useless even if she comes three hundred times!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty can punish me as you wish.
I only beg of Your Majesty to
spare my brother's life.
Consider it as keeping a house dog
to fulfil his duty to Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I beg for Your Majesty's mercy!
Your Majesty!
Get someone to treat her wounds.
And tell her to stay put in her palace.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty! I beg for Your Majesty's mercy!
Considering Nian Gengyao's contributions in
Qinghai, I will spare him of torturous punishment.
I grant Nian Gengyao the option of suicide,
and his son Nian Fu will be executed.
All his other sons over fifteen years old
will be sent to serve in the borderlands.
This matter is almost resolved.
I intend to promote your father to the
second rank in the Ministery of Personnel.
And concurrently, Left Imperial Censor in the Censorate.
Your Majesty's thoughts are profound.
But I'm afraid my father won't be able to fulfill
such responsibilities at his old age.
Your father is getting old,
but it has been my comfort
to have your brilliance by my side.
So this position
is my reward to your father,
as well as to you.
I thank Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Ladyship.
Misses, please rise.
Your Ladyship flatters us.
My Lady has been waiting eagerly.
Please, come in quickly.
It's really warm, just like in the Spring.
My Lady is sensitive to the cold so His Majesty
has sent in braziers already.
- It's really fragrant. What kind of flower is this?
- It's pearl mountain tea.
No one else has it except for the Empress.
- Mother.
- Peace to Your Highness.
If Your Highness won't allow me to bow,
others will fault Your Highness for
improper etiquette.
Mother, please get up and have a seat.
Mother, why didn't you bring Yurao with you today?
Your father was just promoted, and Yurao
has been kept occupied.
She went snow-viewing with the daughters of Mr. Zhou
and Mr. Li from the Valiant Cavalry.
Mother, I was thinking that
girls should stay away from getting
involved in court matters.
Although His Majesty has high regards for father,
we still need to avoid being
"the big tree that attracts the winds."
Now that the Nian family has quieted down
and our family is in His Majesty's good graces,
I hope father will be even more cautious
with his words and actions.
The Nian family serves as a precedent to us.
Your father has always expressed
that it is a lesson on prudence.
Just as Your Highness understands,
his only hobby is collecting classic texts.
I don't think there is much to be cautious of.
That's good.
I have something to ask of you, Mother.
I await Your Highness's order.
Jade has come of age.
Please tell father to select someone -
of good character, and attractive,
among the families in court.
I will take Jade as my honorary sister.
And marry her off in a grand ceremony.
Most certainly, as Your Highness
thinks highly of Jade.
I thank Your Ladyship.
Please keep an eye out for Vermilion as well.
Both Jade and Vermilion grew up with Your Highness.
Good news should come in a pair.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.